RG 136, John Gray & Co., Lisbon, Connecticut
Connecticut State Library
John Gray & Co. records
1819-1831
Connecticut State Library
John Gray & Co. (Lisbon, Conn.)
1.75 cubic feet
John Gray & Co. appears to have operated a general store and cotton factory in Lisbon, Connecticut. The records consist of account books, a cashbook, daybooks, ledgers, letter books, check stubs, and time books.
RG136
1937-006
Historical Note
John Gray & Co. appears to have operated a general store and cotton factory in Lisbon, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The records consist of account books, a cashbook, daybooks, ledgers, letter books, check stubs, and time books.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
John Gray & Co. (Lisbon, Conn.)
Places:
Lisbon (Conn.)
Subjects:
John Gray & Co. (Lisbon, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; General stores -- Connecticut -- Lisbon; Cotton textile industry -- Connecticut -- Lisbon; Cotton manufacture -- Connecticut -- Lisbon; Textile factories -- Connecticut -- Lisbon
Document Types:
Account books; Cashbooks; Daybooks; Checkbooks; Correspondence
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The collection of letterbooks and account books were most likely purchased in 1937 from Mrs. M.F. Linton of Norwich, Connecticut. The records were transferred from RG 069 on December 4, 1975.
Container List
- Records, 1819-1831
  - 1. Daybooks, 1822-1831
    - 1822 March 19 - 1823 July 30 (Volume 1)
      "Blotter 5"
    - 1823 July 30 - 1824 April 3 (Volume 2)
      "Blotter 6"
    - 1824 November 6 - 1825 July 30 (Volume 3)
      "Blotter 8"
    - 1825 August 1 - 1826 February 16 (Box 4)
      "Blotter 9"
    - 1828 March 31- 1829 March 31 (Volume 5)
      Also contains entries for 1830, 1864 January 1 - September 7, 1864 January 1, 1866 August 18.
    - 1829 March 2 - 1830 March 1 (Volume 6)
    - 1830 February 24 - 1831 April 7 (Volume 7)
  - 2. Account books, 1822-1830
    - 1822-1826 (Volume 8)
    - 1824-1827 (Volume 9)
    - 1828-1830 (Volume 10)
  - 3. Cashbook, 1828-1829 (Volume 11)
  - 4. Indexes
    - Index to account book, item 10 (Volume 12)
    - Index to unidentified item (Volume 13)
    - Index to account book, item 8 (Volume 14)
  - 5. Letterbooks, 1821, 1825-1826
    - 1821 (Volume 15)
    - 1824-1826 (Volume 16)
  - 6. Check stubs, 1821-1826 (Volume 17)
  - 7. Account book, 1819-1820 (Volume 18)
    Probably from the cotton factory.
  - 8. Time book, 1824-1826 (Volume 19)